hey blitzers we recently rolled out some
new updates to our reports making it
more user friendly and accurate and in
this video we're going to run through
those updates let's jump in as you can
see we've got a live task on my list and
below that I have done uh a few tasks
over the course of the day we'll head
over to home and in the navigation menu
we'll click reports and I'll go ahead
and choose 30 days uh to view that time
period uh as you can see there's new
stats at the top in this new update
we're actually recording daily session
times with Blitz it so whenever you pull
out Blitz it and run a task live or take
breaks we're recording those sessions
daily to give you more accurate
representation of your daily
productivity within your reports so
let's jump into these stats so you can
see over here we have total work days
essentially for this 30-day time period
total work days represents the days that
I actually worked on Blitz it the days I
pulled up Blitz it and made a task live
and you know did a couple of tasks to
breaks etc those are counted as uh one
day if I did that on a single day within
a 24hour period Then it counts as I have
used Blitz it as one day and you can
mirror that across the daily sessions
graph for as you can see this 30 days
there there should be 17 days that
actually did work uh Within These
individual days and the days that are
empty are which show zero total hours
worked will be days that I didn't
actually I didn't actually pull out
Blitz it or made any task live great so
next up we have total task done task
done essentially across this entire time
period how many tasks did I actually do
within that time period in my case
across those 30 days I did a total of 44
tasks and to get an average of that
across those work days that equals to
2.6 tasks per day and that to be
specific is workday so what we're doing
here is taking this 44 and divide it by
the by 17 your work days which gives you
on average 2.6 tasks per day on average
uh that you're accomplishing across all
your work days next we got total hours
work total hours work is exactly what it
says essentially across the entire time
period how many hours did you work in
Total and again the average of that will
be dividing the 81 hours by 17 total
work days which will give you 4.8 hours
per day or to be more specific per work
day across the time period is your
average finally we have average time per
task how much time on average do you
spend uh in a session per task and this
includes your done tasks as well as your
tasks that are incomplete but have
recorded session times in my case will
be 86 minutes on average across all of
my tasks I'm expected to spend around 86
minutes per task of course give or take
depending on the task some tasks I
probably took way more hours but it's an
average to give you an idea of how much
time you spend on average per task
across those 44 tasks that you completed
within the time period finally of course
we have have the graph sessions and the
graph sessions has a new update making
it more easy and more user friendly
we've converted the metrics to task
breakes and total out of all all of them
for example let's take this session over
here I don't haven't taken much breaks
as you can see I just go straight
complete blazing
24/7 but you can see over here I've got
task 5.6 hours I did I had a 0.2 hour
break so not sure what that would be
maybe 15 minutes or so but from that or
less than that but from that you can see
that it's calculated the total
underneath so the on total I spent 5.6
hours on tasks and on breaks I took 0.2
hours on breaks that total being 5.7
hours across my entire daily session so
I spent in total working let's say 5.7
hours including the break uh and of
course you can turn off these stats
within the graph if you wish great so
that is the new stats below that we have
most productive hour so most productive
hour or hours is essentially across the
time period that you selected which
hours do you have blitzed running the
most session times right and and when we
see that consistency throughout the day
perhaps there's a specific range of
hours or hour that you always are
pulling up Blitz it and running session
times and in that Focus mode then we'll
record that hour for you in my case it's
3:00 p.m. to 400 p.m. finally we have
most productive day across all of your
days in the week across the time period
which day do you have the most sessions
being run in my case is Thursday and
then finally we have most productive
month across all the time period if of
course is within a month then it'll be
that month but if you take a larger
range perhaps 90 days or one year then
you can see out of that you know which
month you had the most sessions run
which will give you the most productive
month and next we have time by list
essentially taking your total time
worked across the time period how is
that divided across your various lists
and here you can see I've worked on
glorify the most 51 hours and the rest
you can see how it is divided uh finally
we have done tasks done tasks gives you
a list of all your done tasks with the
time stamp of the day where you actually
did it according to this uh header as
you can see 26th of February I did all
these tasks on the 25th I did this Etc
and it also gives you an idea of how
early or late you are for example this
task that was 30 minutes late uh early
uh this one early by 1 hour and 19
minutes whereas this task I was late by
1 hour and 56 minutes total time taken
is 3 hours and 16 for example yeah so if
something Z minutes essentially I just
probably marked it as done without
recording in time taken perhaps maybe I
you know outsourced it to someone else
to do it Etc so those are different ways
of how the stats actually look so if you
just mark it as done without adding any
recorded time taken then it'll show at
zero whereas if you have any session
times you can see here there's a session
time of 43 minutes I was 16 minutes
early I probably made this task for 1
hour so there you go 60 minutes early
Etc and now when you see the percentage
here you can see by how much of a
percentage am I uh showing up as early
in my task versus late and this is
divided on the amount of hours stacked
let's say you know you're in total
across the time period you have a total
of uh you know I think I was laate for
one task by quite a lot like 14 hours
late by this task so that could stack up
a lot so the total hours late let's say
you know in total you spend 20 hours
late and in total time early is probably
10 hours so the ratio between those two
will give you the percentage so in my
case I'm 32% of the time I am early
versus 67% of the time late so that is
the new updates to reports we're going
to keep making this more sophisticated
gamified and better and always looking
for your feedback hope this helps guys
that's it for this video take care